Mr. Speaker, pursuant to Clause 4 of Rule 22, I move that the House take from the Speaker's
table the Senate Amendment to the House Joint Resolution 59, recede from its amendment, and concur in the Senate Amendment to open the government now.
Under
Section 2 of House Resolution 368, that motion may be offered only by the Majority Leader or his designee. Parliamentary Inquiry. The Standing
Rule of the House is Rule 22, Clause 4. Is that
correct? That is correct. And the Standing Rule of the House reads,
Mr. Speaker,
When the stage of disagreement has been
reached between -- reached on a bill or a resolution with House or Senate amendments, a motion to dispose of any amendment shall be privileged. Mr. Speaker, my question is, is this parliamentary status of the bill -- does this -- does it meet the requirements of 22/4?
The House has
altered that operation of that standing rule. So I just want to understand, Mr.
Speaker, this standing rule of the House, which I have here, has
been altered by the House. Is that what the Speaker's saying? The House adopted a resolution altering.
A parliamentary inquiry, Mr. Speaker. When was that alteration made? House Resolution 368.
House
Resolution 368, Mr. Speaker, just parliamentary inquiry, I want to make sure I have the right one. I have in my hand H. Res. 368, October 1st, resolved, and Section 2 of that says, any motion pursuant to Clause 4 of Rule 22 relating to the House Joint Resolution may be offered
only by the majority leader or his designee. Is that what you're referring to, Mr. Speaker?
- That is the resolution.
- So, Mr. Speaker, just so I understand the situation, parliamentary inquiry.
H-Res
368 changed the standing rules of the House to take away from any member of the House the privilege of calling up the Senate bill to immediately reopen the government. Is that
right?
It did
change the operation of the standing rule. Right. So,
just parliamentary inquiry, a privileged motion, Mr. Speaker, would have allowed any member of this House, Republican or Democrat, to call up the Senate bill to open the government. Is that right?
The
chair did not give an advisory opinion on that.
But Mr. Speaker, a privileged resolution, as cited in Rule 22-4, the standing rules of the House.
would allow any
member of the House to offer that resolution. Is that right? The chair will not
give an advisory opinion. Well, Mr. Speaker, Parliamentary Inquiry, I
think you just, as I understood, said that that was changed so that it no longer would be a privileged motion for any member, but it would be exclusively the right of the Republican leader or his designee. Am I right about
that?
The House
will follow House Resolution 368. And just, again, Mr.
Speaker, I want
to be absolutely clear
that H. Res.
368 changed the standing rules of the House so that only the Republican leader or his designee could call to open the cover. The gentleman will state his parliamentary
inquiry. Parliamentary inquiry.
Parliamentary inquiry.
I would ask my colleagues whether the majority leader or his designee is on the floor of the house today.
The gentleman
will address -- Parliamentary
inquiry, Mr. Speaker.
This rule
-- The
chair is -- My parliamentary inquiry, and this will be my last one. I just want to understand,
Mr. Speaker.
The
Rules Committee, under the rules of the House, changed the standing rules of the House to take away the right of any member to move to vote to open the government
and gave that right exclusively to the Republican leader. Is that right? The House adopted that resolution. The chair is now
prepared to entertain one minute. I make my motion, Mr. Speaker.
I
renew my motion that under the regular standing rules of the House, Clause 4,
Rule 22, that the House take up the Senate amendments and open the government now.
Under Section 2 of House Resolution 368, that motion may be offered only by the majority leader or his designate. And this,
Mr. Speaker, why were the rules rigged to keep the government shut down? The gentleman will suspend. Well, Mr. Speaker, I
think democracy has been suspended. The gentleman will suspend.
Thank you.